Christophe Foyer

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 • France: (+33) 6-78-56-99-03 US and French citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

Summary:

Mechanical Engineering graduate with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, and aerospace engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

• CAD, FEA and CFD

• *Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)*

• Engineering Hand Calculations

• Server Management and Software Development

Education:

Washington University in Saint Louis

Saint Louis, United States

Aug 2014 – Dec 2017

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering
Study Abroad: - RWTH Aachen, Germany (Summer 2017)

3.14/4.00 GPA

- School for International Training, Iceland (Summer 2015)

Experience:

Tata Steel Europe

Ijmuiden, Netherlands

Apr 2018 – July 2018

Mechanical Engineering Intern

- Successfully built a real-time thermal simulation in Python reducing estimation error by 82.4%
- Estimating slab temperature within 21°C leading to potential savings of one million euros per year
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Mar 2016 - Dec 2017

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead

- Co-led the team to 12th place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

Domaine du Vivier Seasonal farm hand

Le Mesnil Mauger, France

Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

• Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work during the summer

Projects:

Senior Design Project - Low-Cost CPV

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%.

Electric Longboard

Oct 2016 – Dec 2017

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard:

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminium and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing performance and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations

Skills:

CAD / FEA / CFD: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, XFLR5

Programming: Python, MATLAB, Simulink, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication: Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite wet layup (FG/CF), 3D-Printing, GD&T

Software/OS: Microsoft Office Suite, Latex, Windows, Linux

Languages: Bilingual English – French • Basic German and Icelandic

^{*}References available upon request